

### Contact

07872-909-452

🖄 philbower80@outlook.com

11 George Close, Lowestoft, Suffolk, NR32 3LT

https://github.com/PhilBower80

### Skill Key

**Expert** 

Secured

**Proficient** 

**Intermediate** 

**Basic** 

### **Testimonials**

### Kayleigh Hall

Developer Trainer

"Phil tackles any new challenge head on and cares about producing high quality work. He is committed to his projects and will work hard to make a positive impact."

### **Tessa Woodrow**

Project Manager

"Phil has been a keen student ever since he joined the course. He has tackled each challenge with enthusiasm and is always determined to overcome any challenges. He would be a real asset to any company as a junior developer"

## **Philip Bower**

Junior Web Developer

### **Summary**

I am a self motivated, proactive, adaptable and determined person who enjoys working in a team environment or equally solo. I have worked in customer service / sales support for the past 20 years and have gained excellent communication and interpersonal skills. I have long held a desire to work in IT and further to gaining an opportunity to join the Netmatters Scion Coalition scheme I have trained in front and back end technologies to realise my dream. I am now looking to continue this journey as a Junior Web Developer in the real world whilst continuing to learn to improve and gain additional skills in this field.

### Skills

HTML5 400+ hours

Several months of experience both personally and professionally. Comfortable with semantic markup and general structuring.

JavaScript 100+ hours 

Able to use vanilla JavaScript as well as ¡Query and AJAX.

Git 50+ hours

Used frequently while working on projects.

Visual Basic 500+ hours

I have built a stock management system in excel. Using forms to control information that the user enters and I also added a search tool along with the ability to add/edit and delete records.

Laravel 40+ hours

Basic knowledge of the PHP framework.

**CSS3** 400+ hours

Able to manage layouts with both Flexbox and CSS Grid.

PHP 100+ hours

Basic knowledge of the language, including an understanding of the core features.

**SQL** 50+ hours

Experienced using SQL, creating, querying and returning data from databases.

Bootstrap 10+ hours

Basic knowledge and understanding of the bootstrap library to quickly design and customize responsive

sites.

### **Experience**

### Four04 Packaging Ltd

Stock Controller 2018 - 2019

- Built and maintained a spreadsheet using advanced formulae and macros for analysing stock and usage.
- Provided insight to the Commercial Director and Software Developer for requirements across the business for development of a new Management Information System.

# Fourt04 Packaging Ltd (was Polyprint Ltd)

Account Handler 2015 - 2018

- Provided customer service to our largest customer (Four04) by maintaining regular contact through telephone and emails. Liaising with production planning to ensure our customers production targets were met.
- Recording movement of stock in/out of our warehouse and relaying this information to our customer

### **Treehouse**

Treehouse is an online learning community, featuring videos covering a number of topics from basic HTML to C# programming, iOS development, data analysis, and more. By completing courses users can earn points, allowing them to track their progress and see how much they've covered certain areas.

Total Score 17,015

https://teamtreehouse.com/philipbower

### **Introduction to Scion Coalition Scheme**

The Scion Coalition Scheme is an intensive, specially tailored training program being run by Netmatters in order to give willing candidates the opportunity to enter the industry as web developers. Under the supervision of senior web developers, scions generally aim to complete training within six to nine months. The course is intensive and therefore the level of learning achieved is extensive in a short space of time.

#### **Education**

2019-Present

### **Scion Coalition Scheme**

- Undertook an intensive, specially tailored training program under the supervision of senior web developers in the industry. This course is 40 hours per week and simulates employment as a developer to ensure the trainee is prepared for full time employment.
- Studied front-end and back-end development including UI/UX design, mobile development, object-oriented programming and databases.

1996-2001

### **University / Education**

- Lowestoft College HNC: Business Studies
- Kirkley High School A Levels: Psychology (D), General Studies (D).

### **Hobbies**

### Excel/Visual Basic

I have used my interest in programming to develop a stock management system managing 1000's of products using Excel/Visual Basic. This was borne of an interest to learn how to use Visual Basic and help in my previous day to day role as a Stock Controller to improve the basic spreadsheet we used to record stock movements.

### Paddleboarding/kayaking

With the benefit of living so close to the sea and the Norfolk broads I enjoy taking a paddle to explore the local waterways either solo or with a local group.